Istanbul/TURKEY 🏫

+905067788707

brk.krks.41@gmail.com

https://burakkarakus.github.io/go.html in

Burak Karakus

Cover Letter

I have been working as a Software Engineer since 2014. I worked in many large-scale projects that was getting millions of daily users. For the most time of my professional experience, I worked in both frontend and backend of softwares. However, most recently, I have been working mostly on creating, maintaining, and orchestrating backend services and APIs for many platforms such as iOS/Android client applications, chatbots, websites.

After my first years of developing backend technologies, I started to realize that I need to be much more planned and conscious about it. I have mostly written RESTful services on NodeJS environment, abiding the rules defined in OpenAPI 3.0 Specs, with the help of TypeScript. In the design process of a service, I usually try to follow the seven stages of action defined by Donald Norman, as quoted in Design and Build Great Web APIs by Mike Amundsen. I try to write the code as clean as possible, with the rules defined in The Twelve-Factor App Manifest. Planning is the most important phase in a software development lifecycle and committing to that value changed my vision and feel of my professional life.

Programming Skills

- NodeJS Environment
- Javascript/TypeScript
- NestJS
- VuelS
- React
- .NET Framework / C#
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL (+TimescaleDB)

- HTML
- CSS (SCSS, LESS)
- Flutter
- Java
- MSSQL

Toolchain

- AWS: I have been using AWS DevOps & Developer Related Services for 4 years professionally.
- Microsoft Azure: I have been using Azure DevOps & Developer Related Services for 2 year professionally and I am the responsible and accountable person in my current occupation.
- **Git** (Github, Bitbucket, AWS CodeCommit)
- Google Maps, Directions, Dialogflow
- Microsoft LUIS
- Facebook SDK's and API's
- WhatsApp Business SDK & API's

Experience

01.07.2022 - PRESENT

Senior Software Engineer / Orion Innovation

02.10.2020 - PRESENT

Senior Software Engineer / WeWALK Inc, Istanbul

- Handling all API/backend service needs of WeWALK client apps and smartcane, with strictly abiding the rules defined in The Twelve Factor App manifest (https://12factor.net)
- Using NodeJS environment with TypeScript, via expressjs, pm2, etc...
- Azure Services: App Services, Functions, Event Hubs, CosmosDB, Azure Cache for Redis etc. Azure DevOps for handling CI/CD pipelines of our API
- Creating and managing real time time-series data collection and aggregation using PostgreSQL with TimescaleDB extension
- Creating and managing our real-time video call solution's backend, using Azure WebPubSub and Websocket technologies, and providing a UI, which I created in React, for our agents to help our visually impaired customers to find their way
- Helping our operational departments by enabling them to use admin panel written in VueJS, which is consuming the same API that we created for our customers

02.10.2017 - 02.10.2020

Software Engineer / Turkish Airlines, Istanbul

- Crafted software in the Digital Innovation/Lean Product Development Department to make the experience of our customers and/or colleagues better.
- Contributed to the building process Turkish Airlines's new chatbot, Boti, which is planned to work
 on the platforms like Messenger, WhatsApp, Telegram, and Bip; written in TypeScript on NodeJS
 platform, running serverlessly on AWS Lambda.
- Designed and implemented the building/development process of Turkish Cargo's new chatbot, <u>Cargy</u>, which has been in use of many of Turkish Cargo customers since June 2020. I was responsible for both developing the application and DevOps while communicating with related work units in Turkish Cargo.
- Followed up the technological developments in -insert here any catchy trendy concept names like
 AI, ML, Blockchain etc.- and integrate them into the Turkish Airlines' processes by producing
 solutions with the in-unit development team or with the start-ups that we have contact amongst the
 national/international start-up ecosystem and implementing these solutions to facilitate our
 customers' and/ or our employees' lives.

01.09.2015 - 01.10.2017

Full-stack Web Developer / oBilet.com, Istanbul

- Used HTML/CSS, JavaScript (Vanilla and jQuery), webpack, ASP.NET MVC, MSSQL, AWS tech stack.
- Full redesign of bus ticketing system with a 5 men team
- Adding new feature, flight ticketing system, to the newly developed code based
- Responsible for managing admin pages for internal use

01.06.2014 - 02.10.2015

Junior Web Developer / Onluk Duzen, Istanbul

 Contributed to multiple web-based projects using ASP.NET MVC, JQuery/JavaScript/AJAX, HTML5/CSS3,MSSQL/MongoDB/Redis.

Education

2014

Computer Engineering (B. Sc.) / Istanbul Kültür University

English Preparation School (1 Year) + 4 years of CE

Activities

Oualifications

- İstanbul Fatih Municipality Tourist Guide (AskMe Project)
- Ted Conferences, Translator (https://www.ted.com/profiles/1214249/translator)